{
    "id": "810608da47004307bd772bd33a53f2f0",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "An addressing machine ……………………… the handling of bulk mail.",
            "description": "We use the simple present tense to talk about facts.",
            "answers": [
                "is facilitating",
                "facilitate",
                "facilitates"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The old shepherd at age 95 still …………………………… the full possession of his faculties.",
            "description": "We use the simple present tense to talk about facts.",
            "answers": [
                "has enjoyed",
                "would enjoy",
                "enjoys"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Jim is an extrovert who ………………………….. to meet people.",
            "description": "We use the simple present tense to talk about facts.",
            "answers": [
                "love",
                "loves",
                "is loving"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Let’s see how she ………………………….. herself from this embarrassing situation.",
            "description": "In subordinate clauses we often use a simple present tense to indicate future. ",
            "answers": [
                "is extricating",
                "extricates",
                "has extricated"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The hillside …………………………. with an exuberant growth of weeds.",
            "description": "We need a passive verb here.",
            "answers": [
                "covers",
                "is covering",
                "is covered"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The play was so successful that it ………………………. an extended engagement at the local theater.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we need a past verb in the subordinate clause as well. ",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "have",
                "had"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "An extensive desert …………………………. much of northern Africa.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "covers",
                "is covering",
                "has covered"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "During World War II, many Germans ………………………… in the United States.",
            "description": "To simply state that something happened in the past, we use the simple past tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "were settling",
                "had settled",
                "settled"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The novel Tom Sawyer …………………………….. 19th century life in the United States.",
            "description": "Use the simple present tense to talk about facts. ",
            "answers": [
                "is exemplifying",
                "exemplifies",
                "was exemplifying"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Chess ………………………….. a lot of mental exertion.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is requiring",
                "requires",
                "has required"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I have bought a chicken in case your father ……………………… stay to lunch.",
            "description": "Should + infinitive can be used with the same meaning as might + infinitive after in case. ",
            "answers": [
                "should",
                "might",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "In case the ranch burns down, we ……………………….. the insurance money.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "get",
                "will get",
                "would get"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}